[{"Question":"A and B can do a piece of work in 72 days. B and C can do it in 120 days. A and C can do it in 90 days. In how many days all three together can do the work ?","option 1":" 80 days","option 2":" 100 days","option 3":"60 days","option 4":"150 days","answer":"60 days"},{"Question":"A is as efficient as B and C together. Working together A and B can complete a work in 36 days and C alone can complete it in 60 days. A and C work together for 10 days. B alone will complete the remaining work in:","option 1":"88 days","option 2":"110 days","option 3":"84 days","option 4":"90 days","answer":"110 days"},{"Question":"Three pipes A, B can fill the tank in 12, 20 hrs respectively and C can empty the tank in 30 hours. If the pipes are opened alternatively for 1 hour starting with A and drain pipe is kept open all the time. How much time will it take to fill the tank.","option 1":"12","option 2":"30","option 3":"15","option 4":"20","answer":"30"},{"Question":"A and B can do a work together in 18 days. A is three times as efficient as B. In how many days can B alone complete the work?","option 1":"60 days","option 2":"72 days","option 3":"54 days","option 4":"64 days","answer":"72 days"},{"Question":"A alone can do a piece of work in 15 days, while B alone can do it in 20 days. They work together for 6 days and the rest of the work is done by C in 6 days. If they get Rs 800 for the whole work, how should they divide the money?","option 1":"Rs. 320, Rs. 240 and Rs. 240","option 2":"Rs. 640, Rs. 280 and Rs. 260","option 3":"Rs. 320, Rs. 420 and Rs. 360","option 4":"Rs. 360, Rs. 420 and Rs. 240","answer":"Rs. 320, Rs. 240 and Rs. 240"},{"Question":"The number of mainas and parrots in an aviary is in the ratio of (4x + 5) : 4x. If 25 mainas and 10 parrots are added to the aviary, then, the ratio would change to 5: 3. How many mainas are there in the aviary at initial?","option 1":"20","option 2":"30","option 3":"35","option 4":"25","answer":"25"},{"Question":"The cost of printing a book increased from Rs. 96 to Rs. 120 from the year 2013 to 2018, such that the total money spent on printing books by a printing press increased in the ratio 5Â âˆ¶Â 6. If the printing press printed 200 books in the year 2013, how many books did they print in the year 2018?","option 1":"176","option 2":"192","option 3":"216","option 4":"252","answer":"192"},{"Question":"There are 240 workers and an amount of Rs. 2880 is to be divided among them. The ratio of total amount received to men and women is 5 : 4 and the ratio of the amount given to each man and each woman is 5 : 8. Find the number of men.","option 1":"120","option 2":"140","option 3":"160","option 4":"180","answer":"160"},{"Question":"A and B started a business in partnership. The ratio between the investments of A and B was 5: 4. If A invested for 12 months and at the end of the year the ratio of prot was 15: 8, then for how much time B invested?","option 1":"8 months","option 2":"9 months","option 3":"6 months","option 4":"10 months","answer":"8 months"},{"Question":"4 years hence, the ratio of ages A and B will be 5: 7 and 6 years hence, the ratio of ages will be 11: 15, then and their present ages.","option 1":"20 years, 26 years","option 2":"16 years, 24 years","option 3":"18 years, 28 years","option 4":"12 years, 18 years","answer":"16 years, 24 years"},{"Question":"if 50% of (x-y) =30% of (x+y), then what percentage of x is y?","option 1":"25%","option 2":"40%","option 3":"400%","option 4":"33.33%","answer":"25%"},{"Question":"What percent of 3.6kg is 72 gms ?","option 1":"32%","option 2":"22%","option 3":"12%","option 4":"2%","answer":"2%"},{"Question":"A travels 25% faster than B. They started their journey from a point P to another point Q and reach at the same time on point Q. Distance between P and Q is 85 km. On the way, however, A lost about 20 minutes while stopping for petrol. What was the speed of B?","option 1":" 51 km/hr","option 2":"50 km/hr","option 3":"45 km/hr","option 4":"None of these","answer":" 51 km/hr"},{"Question":"Speed of boat in still water is 9 km/hr. Stream speed initially is 2 km/hr but it increases by 3 km/hr after every hour. Find the time after which boat will come back to the position where it started.(in hour)","option 1":"5(5/8)","option 2":"5(3/8)","option 3":"4(3/4)","option 4":"None of these","answer":"5(5/8)"},{"Question":"Running at the speed of 3 km/hr., a person reaches his destination 10 minutes later than usual time. if he increases his speed by 1 km/hr., he reaches his destination 15 min earlier. and the distance to his destination.","option 1":"10 km","option 2":"12 km","option 3":"5 km","option 4":"4 km","answer":"5 km"},{"Question":"A man can row 52 km upstream and 42 km downstream in 10 hours. It is also known that he can row 66 km downstream and 60 km upstream in 13 hours. Find the speed of the man in still water.","option 1":" 8 km/hr","option 2":"12 km/hr","option 3":"6 km/hr","option 4":"10 km/h","answer":"10 km/h"},{"Question":"A sum of money amounts to 5,200 in 5 years and to 5,680 in 7 years at simple interest. The rate of interest per annum is-","option 1":"3%","option 2":"4%","option 3":"5%","option 4":"6%","answer":"6%"},{"Question":"In how many years a sum of Rs. 3000 will yield an interest of Rs. 1080 at 12% per annum simple interest?","option 1":"4 years","option 2":"3 years","option 3":"5 years","option 4":" 6 years","answer":"3 years"},{"Question":"What annual instalment will discharge a debt of â‚¹ 6450 due in 4 years at 5% simple interest?","option 1":"1500","option 2":"1835","option 3":"1935","option 4":"1950","answer":"1500"},{"Question":"Alipta got some amount of money from her father. In how many years will the ratio of the money and the interest obtained from it be 10:3 at the rate of 6% simple interest per annum?","option 1":" 7 years","option 2":"3 years","option 3":"5 years","option 4":"4 years","answer":"5 years"}]
